Hello everyone and welcome
to EnglishPod, my name is Marco.
My name is Catherine
and we've been traveling
around the world eating
different foods from
different countries and
today we're in Thailand.
That's right Thai food
is one of the most
popular types of food
around the world especially
because of that specific Asian taste it has
and so we're going to jump right into this
dialogue today and see what
we have prepared for you today.
What did you cook?
Well as you know I was
in Thailand last month
and I took a cooking class so I
prepared some of my favorite dishes.
Great idea as long as I don't get food
poisoning so what is on the menu tonight?
Okay for starters we have Tom Yum
soup it's a bit spicy but really good.
This is delicious the ginger and
lemon grass really give it a nice taste.
Now this next dish is one of
the most famous foreigners
call it papaya salad but the
proper name is Tom Sam.
It is a spicy salad made
from a mix of fresh
vegetables including shredded
unripe papaya and tomato.
This is delicious the
combination of salons
spicy is really interesting I
could have this every day.
Okay now for the last and
best dish in my opinion.
This is called pad Thai.
It stir fried noodles
with eggs, fish sauce,
tamarind juice, red chili
pepper, plus bean sprouts,
shrimp and tofu garnished with
crushed peanuts and coriander.
It's practically Thailand's national dish.
Wow this is great I never knew Thai
food was so creative and delicious.
Want some more?
It's stuffed.
Alright so we've got
a number of different
dishes we'd like to talk
about as well as phrases
so let's look at some of those dishes and
important keywords in language takeaway.
Language takeaway.
Alright so the first word
we have on language
takeaway today is food
poisoning so we don't
want to get food poisoning
when having this any meal.
Any meal now that's right
food poisoning is a bad thing.
Now this is something
that happens when you
eat bad food or dirty
food basically you get
very very sick and you feel like you
have to vomit you have to throw up.
That's right so your stomach hurts you feel
like you have to throw up you may be going
to the bathroom very often that
means usually you have food poisoning.
Alright and so people
often associate food
poisoning with food
that you eat on the street
maybe dirty your food but this is something
you should be very careful of when you're
traveling not to Thailand
alone but maybe to
any other country you
can get it in America
you can get it in Mexico so
just something to be careful of.
That's right so apart from that
we're going to jump into our
first dish for today we're having
soup called Tom Yam soup.
Tom Yam soup now this is one of my favorite
soups it's quite spicy isn't it Marco?
Very spicy but very very good as well
it has a kind of citric taste like lemon.
It does and it's very
yellow or orange colored
and it's a very very
common dish on Thai
restaurant menus and
there's some key ingredients
in this soup that I think
are important to discuss.
They're often found
in Thai food and other
kinds of Asian food
the first one is ginger.
Ginger that's right this is a root it
kind of looks like a potato almost.
It does it's usually white in a hazel arms
you know it kind of it's not a round object
it's got pointy little
arms that's right and
ginger is the characteristic taste of
ginger is kind of strong and bitter.
It is quite strong
you'll find it in Japanese
food oftentimes you
get pickled ginger to
eat it's like a pink
food get wasushi other
times in like Chinese
cooking it's something
that's chopped up with garlic and cooked
in oil so ginger is a very important one.
That's right so in this
soup we have ginger
and we also have
lemon grass so this is very
interesting because it's not very
easily found around the world.
That's right this is very
common in southeast
Asian cooking and you
might have a hard time
finding it in places
like America where it's
not really a part of
the cuisine but lemon
grass is very distinct it has a very strong
flavor and it's actually quite long it's
green and long it looks a
bit like celery but it's harder.
That's right that's right and the taste
that it gives it is a little bit citric kind
of like lemon almost.
That's right but you're
going to find this in
soups like tommyam
or other things so lemon
grass is another one.
And then moving on
to our next dish which is
one of the most I think
the most popular dishes
of all Thailand is the
famous pad Thai pad Thai.
Now this is absolutely
my favorite Thai dish
and I know that's very
cliche it's something
that everyone says
but it's true you know
this is a great dish you
can buy on the street
you can buy it in a restaurant
it's basically a noodle dish right?
That's right it's a stir
fried noodles with eggs
and peanuts are the most
like the key ingredients in there.
That's right but you
might also get a little
bit of hot red pepper
some sugar some lime
and the noodles are
flat they're not round.
That's right and
actually one of the key
ingredients also that gives it this
very distinct taste is tamarind juice.
All right tamarind juice
this is again another
one of those flavors
from southeast Asia
that you might not find in many
other places certainly not America.
Now tamarind they're
funny looking at things
they look like peas
but they're dark brown.
That's right so tamarind
juice gives it this
kind of sweet flavor
so this is the interesting
thing about pad Thai
is that you have the
sweet flavors from the
tamarind juice from even
the fish sauce combined with chili so
it's kind of like a spicy very sweet taste.
And then you have
citrus you have some lime
maybe and some sugar
so it's a lot of different
tastes and flavors but it's a
really magical combination.
That's right so that's
all we have for language
take away when we take
another listen to a dialogue.
What did you cook?
Well as you know I was
in Thailand last month
and I took a cooking class so I
prepared some of my favorite dishes.
Great idea as long as I don't get food
poisoning so what is on the menu tonight?
Ok first starters we have tamyam
soup it's a bit spicy but really good.
This is delicious the ginger and
lemon grass really give it a nice taste.
Now this next dish is
one of the most famous
foreigners call it papaya salad
but the proper name is Tom Sam.
It is a spicy salad made
from a mix of fresh
vegetables including shredded
unripe papaya and tomato.
This is delicious the
combination of salad
spasias really interesting I
could have this every day.
Ok now for the last and
best dish in my opinion.
This is called pad
Thai it stir fried noodles
with eggs fish sauce
tamarind juice red chili
pepper plus bean
sprouts shrimp and tofu
garnished with crushed
peanuts and coriander.
It's practically Thailand's national dish.
Wow this is great I never knew Thai
food was so creative and delicious.
Want some more?
I'm stuffed.
Alright we're back so now let's take a look
at four key phrases on fluency builder.
Fluency builder.
So first up we have the phrase on
the menu what's on the menu tonight.
That's right that person
asked well so what's
on the menu and by
saying this we're saying
well what are we having for dinner what are
we going to eat that's right so you might
want to think okay menu I'm going to look
at the menu but you could even say this at
home where there is
no menu this is a spoken
language way of saying
what are we eating
tonight right that's
right what's for dinner
what's what what are
we eating what's on
the menu even though as you said there's
no menu that's right and after that we have
another phrase it's
really important we say
for starters we're going
to have this or that
so for starters that's
right we said for
starters we are having a
soup a tummyam soup so
a starter dish is
something that you have to
begin the meal a small
dish maybe that's right
start starter so a
starter is a noun it's a
thing and it's something
you eat at the beginning
usually it's not very heavy not a steak
would never be a starter right right right
alright so here we have
tummyam soup which is our
starter and after that
we have the national dish
now this is a great
phrase right we had the pat
Thai which is considered
to be the national dish
and so usually every
country has their national
dish something that's
unique or that a country
is famous for like for
example China would be
famous for kungpao
chicken kungpao chicken yeah
in America you might
even say that apple pie
is the most you know
important national dish
but do you guys have
one in Ecuador which you
have some of this I would
say I have no idea which
would be it's very not
not very well known maybe
so each it is kind of
shared between Peru and
Ecuador like maybe in
Argentina you would say
steak steak is a national
dish yeah absolutely
or in Mexico you know
like tacos or enchiladas
stuff like that or in Italy
spaghetti bolognese
that's right all right
so we have we have a
number of different
countries in each country
maybe has one or two
national dishes these are
very special dishes that
that are important for
that country that's right
so we have our national
dishes and after we
finished dinner we ate so
much that we say I'm
stuffed I'm stuffed now
this is a common phrase
that you will hear at the
end of a meal when
you've eaten and eaten and
eaten and eaten and it
just means I'm full I'm full
I'm not eat anymore
yeah I'm stuffed so stuffed
means that I'm full of
things now it's it's a very
informal way of saying
I'm full right because if
somebody says would you
like some more soup you say
no thank you I'm full
right but if you're with
friends you can say oh
I just had so much pizza
I'm stuffed that's
right so it's a little
bit more informal but
a lot more native like
that's right all right so let's take a
listen to our dialogue one last time
what did you cook
well as you know I was in
Thailand last month
and I took a cooking class
so I prepared some of
my favorite dishes great
idea as long as I don't
get food poisoning
so what is on the menu
tonight okay for starters
we have Tom Yum
soup it's a bit spicy but
really good this is delicious
the ginger and lemongrass
really give it a nice
taste now this next dish
is one of the most
famous foreigners call it
papaya salad but the
proper name is Tom Sam
it is a spicy salad made
from a mix of fresh
vegetables including
shredded unripe and papaya
and tomato this is delicious the combination
of salad spicy is really interesting
I could have this every day okay now
for the last and best dish in my opinion
this is called pad Thai it stir-fried
noodles with eggs fish sauce tamarind juice
red chili pepper plus
bean sprouts shrimp and
tofu garnished with crushed
peanuts and coriander
it's practically Thailand's
national dish wow
this is great I never
knew Thai food was so
creative and delicious
lots of more I'm stuffed
all right so speaking of
Thai food it's very famous
around the world but
it's very spicy it can be
very spicy and what always
surprises me about Thai
food is that the salads
might be the spiciest
things on the menu yeah
you know people like to eat
many different salads
you have like a chai mai
chicken salad or you have
a papaya salad but these
are really really spicy
yeah that's right we saw
in our dialogue they were
eating papaya salad and
it's very interesting
because it has this fruit
papaya and it has some
other vegetables as well
but the salad is very
very spicy itself that's
right and you would
never think of a fruit salad
as being something
that's spicy in America you
think of it as being
pretty tame pretty boring
but that's the kind of
what gives it a certain
attraction to it right
absolutely and I don't know
if you're a big fan of
Thai food I certainly am
and I really like that
about Thai food that you
can have these really
spicy dishes but there's just
so much flavor there's
so many things happening
lemongrass sugar lime
fish sauce yeah it's very
very good and speaking
of national dishes this is
actually a very interesting
question because as we
mentioned a couple of
countries have national dishes
like Italy and different
places but what about in
your country do you have
a national dish or what
would you consider to
be your national dish that's
right so we'd love to
hear from you guys what's
your national dish
tell us all about it what
it tastes like and even
if there's some history
tell us about that too
our website is EnglishPod.
com all right we'll
see you guys there bye